(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon
Attention / ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: Notice to Visitors
2次販売グッズ
2nd Wave Merchandise Sales
ファンからのメッセージ
Messages from Fans
だから
So,
君のこと大好き 大好き 大好き 大好き 大好き
I love you, love you, love you, love you, love you so much!
溢れるこの愛は
This overflowing love
きっと止まらない
surely won't stop!
アイ アイ アイ I love you!
I, I, I, I love you!
アイアイアイアイ あいらぶゆー！
Ai, ai, ai, ai, I love you!
もっと
More!
好きになった？愛しちゃって！
Did you fall in love? Love me!
夢見るハートが ぴょんぴょんぴょん
My dreaming heart goes hop, hop, hop!
アナタに落ちて あびゃあびゃあびゃ
Falling for you... oh my, oh my!
こんなになっても
Even if I end up like this,
今は抜け出せない
I can't escape now!
どうしたもんかの ぬいぬいぬい
What should I do? Nui, nui, nui!
助けて君的 あほいほいほい
Save me with your Ahoy-hoy-hoy!
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More! More! More! More!
好きになった？愛してね！
Did you fall in love? Please love me!
アニメにハマって、歌いたくなっちゃった！
I got hooked on anime, and now I really want to sing!
推しのシーン見ながらカラオケ歌えるなんて…
To think I can sing karaoke while watching my favorite scenes...
尊すぎてツラいっ！
It's so precious it hurts!
歌いたいアニゲーソング見つけよう！
Let's find the anime and game songs you want to sing!
JOYSOUND！
JOYSOUND!
吉野家でご飯しよ♪
Let's eat at Yoshinoya!
ぎゅう…
Beef...
ぎゅう、ぎゅう…
Beef, beef...
ぎゅう〜 うま！
Beef... Delicious!
元祖の本気、召し上がれ。牛丼は吉野家。
Taste the dedication of the original. Yoshinoya is the place for beef bowls.
やっぱこれだな！
This is definitely the one!
本日は、ホロライブ...
Today, Hololive...
サードジェネレーションライブ、『キララン大作戦 最強アイドル お寿司かないでしょに』に
Welcome to the 3rd Generation Live, "Kiraran Daisakusen: The Strongest Idols,
ご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
You Have to Support Us, Right?!" Thank you so much for coming!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure everyone enjoys the live show to the very end, we have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, audio recording, and the use of recording equipment during the show are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
The venue is non-smoking. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず、近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If you happen to feel unwell, please do not push yourself and inform a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、
Moshing, diving, throwing objects onto the stage,
他の人の迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
and any other acts that cause trouble or disrupt the performance are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、
Also, cameras for video streaming and photography are inside the venue,
客席が映り込む場合があります。
and the audience area may be captured.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは、『キララン大作戦Day2』です。
Also, the hashtag for this live is #キララン大作戦Day2.
ハッシュタグを使って、たくさん盛り上げてください！
Please use the hashtag and get everyone hyped up!
それでは、開演まであと少しです。
Now then, it is almost time for the show to start.
君たちの声を、いっぱい聞かせてください！
Let us hear your voices loud and clear!
そして、今からちょっと3期生で円陣を組もうと思っているんですが...
And now, we 3rd generation members are about to form a huddle...
マイクを通さずやりますので、ちょっと静かにして、耳を澄ませていただきたく...
We'll do it without our microphones, so please be quiet and listen closely...
はい、いくんで、ちょっとしんと待っててな。静かにね。
Alright, here we go, so please wait quietly. Shh, okay?
せーの...
Ready, set...
3期生、いくぞー！
3rd Generation, let's go!
おー！
Oh!
hololive 3rd Generation Live
兎田ぺこら
[Usada Pekora]
不知火フレア
[Shiranui Flare]
白銀ノエル
[Shirogane Noel]
宝鐘マリン
[Houshou Marine]
きゅるるん大作戦
[Title: Kyururun Daisakusen]
超アイドル 伝説のガールは欲張り
Super idol! The legendary girls are greedy
笑い合って もっと可愛くなる
Laughing together, we'll become even cuter
Oh yeah yeah
と、思いきやお出かけ おめかしして
Just when you thought so, we're going out all dressed up
他人なのに 家族みたいで
Even though we aren't related, we're like a family
Ruru Rurairai 身体測定
Ruru Rurairai, physical examination
Ruru Rurairai 生体セッション
Ruru Rurairai, biological session
喜怒哀楽を全自動で アシストさ
Automatically assisting all your emotions
でっかくなっていきたいよね
We want to grow big, don't we?
でも小っちゃなことも大事にして
But we also cherish the little things
ひとつ、ふたつ 傷ついても
Even if we get hurt once or twice
ハグして触れるのが正しいね
Hugging and touching each other is only right
だからエンターテイン (エンターテイン！)
So let's entertain! (Entertain!)
うしろだって見えてる
We can see the back rows too!
画面の向こうも届いてる
And reaching those beyond the screen!
光の海を泳ごう！
Let's swim in this sea of lights!
超アイドル 伝説のガールは欲張り
Super idol! The legendary girls are greedy
愛されたいし 踊りまくりたい 君じゃなきゃやだ
We want to be loved and dance away! It has to be you!
絶好調です！
We're in top form!
狙い撃ちで 君にウィンク
Taking aim, we wink at you
やっぱり伝説のガールでめっちゃハッピー
Being legendary girls makes us so happy after all
応援したいし 恋もしたいし 叶っちゃうよ、やった！
Wanting to support and fall in love, they'll all come true, yay!
先頭走る
Running at the front
もちろん君と！
Of course, together with you!
笑い合って もっと可愛くなる
Laughing together, we'll become even cuter
Oh yeah yeah
せっかく近くなったんだから 乗り越える壁もデカい
Since we've gotten so close, the walls to overcome are huge too
それってうんとエンタメでしょ？
But isn't that what makes it so entertaining?
君が想ってるより ずっと君のこと想ってる
We think about you way more than you think we do
どうかなどうかな
I wonder, I wonder...
焦がれた夢には近づけてるかな
If we're getting any closer to our longed-for dreams
この涙があるから 頑張れるんだ 聞かせて
These tears are what keep us going, so let us hear you!
超最上のガールは幸せ
The ultimate girls are so happy
愛されて生きてる 感謝しちゃって 下向く暇ない
Living with your love, full of gratitude, with no time to look down
テンポアップし続けていく
We'll keep stepping up the tempo
見たい景色へ！
Toward the scenery we want to see!
世界に達して (はい！ はい！)
Reaching the world! (Hey! Hey!)
光を浴びてダンス (はい！ はい！)
Dancing bathed in light! (Hey! Hey!)
いますぐアピール (はい！ はい！)
Showing off right now! (Hey! Hey!)
みんなで作ってく
Creating this together
イェーイ！
Yeah!
あ、そこのきみも 盛り上がっていくぞ！
Ah, you over there too, let's pump it up!
切り出せ、まだまだ 声 出せますよね！
Let's start it off, you can still scream louder, right?!
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
ゆらいでも がんばっちゃ
Even if we waver, we'll do our best!
ほめられて伸びるは当たってるよね
It's true that we grow when praised, right?
この空間が宝物ね
This space is a treasure, isn't it?
ケガはないわ 笑う
We're unhurt, so we laugh!
君と一緒に！
Together with you!
超アイドル！てんのガールは欲張り
Super Idol! The perfect 10 girls are greedy.
愛されたいし 夢だって見てみたい 君とじゃなきゃやだっ
We want to be loved and dream! It has to be with you!
てってこ 超絶
Running along, super-duper...
狙い撃ちで 君にウインク
with a sharpshot, winking at you!
やっぱ てんのガールで めっちゃハッピー
As expected, being perfect 10 girls makes us super happy!
あれもしたいし これもしたいし 叶っちゃう
We want to do this and that, and they'll all come true!
てってこ 走る
Running along...
もちろん君と 笑い合って もっと可愛くなる
of course with you, laughing together and becoming even cuter!
どこまででも行けちゃう気がする
I feel like we can go anywhere!
Oh yeah yeah!
今日はこのまま さようならじゃないよ
Today is not going to end with a goodbye just like this.
手をとってくれたなら
If you would take my hand...
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に 君を連れていくよ保存
I'll take you away on a night where even secrets seem to fall asleep.
言い訳ばかりに 地団駄の有象無象
Complaining all the time, stamping their feet, the rabble...
ハニハニ ダリダリ マジナ話 どっちどっちが好きなのよ
Honey, honey, darling, darling, seriously, which one do you like?
だめ だめ だめ
No, no, no!
よそ見しないで
Don't look away!
だめ だめ だめ
No, no, no!
もう逃げ出したい？
Do you want to run away already?
手遅れじゃない？
Isn't it too late?
逃げるしかない
There's no choice but to run!
もっとちゃんと愛してよ
Love me more properly!
反対方向
In the opposite direction!
WANTED!
言い訳ばかり
Nothing but excuses...
次はペコラ！
Next is Pekora!
全力ジャンピングいくぺこらー！
Let's do full-power jumping, peko!
今日も明日を追いかけっこなしで
Today, as well, let's chase tomorrow without playing tag,
はい！
Yes!
黄金の蝶 舞い上がれ
Fly high, golden butterfly!
今宵もさあ 踊るよ
Tonight as well, let's dance!
賛美 散在 恋シャワー
Praise, squandering, love shower!
刹那を生きるよ
I'll live in the moment!
瞬間クライマックス
Instant climax!
憂き世 忘れて 狂い咲く
Forget the fleeting world and bloom madly!
激しく 早く 早く
Passionately, faster and faster!
ディスコティークに
In the discotheque...
バイバイ仮面
Bye-Bye, mask!
ディスコティークに
In the discotheque...
バイバイ仮面
Bye-Bye, mask!
イェーイ！
Yay!
Day 2！
Day 2!
Day 2 始まりましたー！
Day 2 has begun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあ早速自己紹介からしていきましょうか！
Now, let's get right into our self-introductions!
していきましょう！
Let's do it!
じゃあみんな、ぺこら久しぶりのあの挨拶行くから、分かってるよねみんな！
All right, everyone, I'm doing my signature greeting after a long time, so you know what to do, right?!
どの挨拶だ？
Which greeting?
あれだ！
That one!
あれしかない！
It can only be that one!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
ドドンガドンドン、全人類VTuber化計画...
Dodongadondon, All Humanity VTuber-ification...
全、ん？
All, huh?
噛んだ！
She stumbled!
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
もう一回ね！もう一回！
One more time! One more time!
いきます！
Here I go!
ドドンガドンドン！全VTuberの中で一番可愛いのは誰だー？！
Dodongadondon! Who is the cutest of all VTubers?!
ドドンガドンドン！
Dodongadondon!
上手くできました！
I did it perfectly!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあ次はフレア！
Next up is Flare!
はい！じゃあフレアは、「はい、ダーリン！」って言うので、「はい、ハニー！」って返してください！
Yes! I will say "Yes, darling!", so please reply with "Yes, honey!"!
おっけー！
Okay!
いきますよー！
Here we go!
はい、ダーリン！
Yes, darling!
ありがとうございまーす！ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
Thank you so much! I'm Shiranui Flare of Hololive 3rd Gen!
そして、
And next...
はい！えーどうしよっかな。え、じゃあ「こんまっする！」って言うから、普通に「こんまっする！」って...
Okay! Um, what should I do? Well, since I'll say "Konmuscle!", please just say "Konmuscle!" back...
「こんまっする」でいいの？
Is "Konmuscle" fine?
牛丼は？
What about beef bowl?
牛丼もね、牛丼はまあ、
Beef bowl too, well, beef bowl is...
あ、やべ、やべ！
Ah, oops, oops!
あぶない、あぶない！
Dangerous, dangerous!
よし！いくぞ！
All right! Here we go!
せーの、こんまっするー！
Ready, Konmuscle!
はい！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
Yes! I'm Shirogane Noel of Hololive 3rd Gen!
よろしくー！
Nice to meet you!
そして、
And next...
君たち！本物のバイバイ仮面は誰ー？！
You guys! Who is the real Bye-Bye Mask?!
違うでしょ！
No way!
本物のバイバイ仮面じゃないけど、バイバイ仮面！
I'm not the real Bye-Bye Mask, but Bye-Bye Mask!
バイバイ仮面！
Bye-Bye Mask!
ペコちゃんに船長取られるし、ノエルにバイバイ仮面取られるし...
Peko-chan took my 'Captain' title, and Noel took 'Bye-Bye Mask'...
本物のバイバイ仮面は？
What about the real Bye-Bye Mask?
本物のバイバイ仮面、ノエルに選ばれたわけだからね。
Noel was chosen as the real Bye-Bye Mask, after all.
そう、悲しい。ということでね、はーい！ホロライブ3期生宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです！
Yeah, sad. Anyway, hi! I'm Houshou Marine, Captain of Houshou Pirates of Hololive 3rd Gen!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ついに、Day 2！
Finally, Day 2!
Day 2！
Day 2!
なんか、昨日と衣装違くない？
Wait, isn't our outfit different from yesterday?
ねー！
Yeah!
あれ、気づきましたか皆さん！
Oh, did everyone notice?!
昨日とちょっと...
A bit different from yesterday...
悪魔になっちゃった！
We turned into devils!
あら、天使から悪魔っぽくなってしまったかな？
Oh, did we change from angels to devil-like?
そうなんですよね。
That's right.
実はこれ、初めて公開するんですよね！
Actually, we're revealing this for the first time, right?!
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
みんなびっくりしたかな？
Was everyone surprised?
かわいい！
So cute!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
でも悪魔って、結構マリンは小悪魔系で売ってるんで、かなりシナジーがあるかも。
But with devils, Marine is pretty much marketed as a little devil, so there might be a lot of synergy.
ぺこらも小悪魔系でやってるから、シナジーあるよ！
Pekora is also doing the little devil thing, so we have synergy too!
え、お前は...
Wait, you are...
ただの悪魔でしょ！
You're just a straight-up devil!
お前はただの悪魔！
You're just a demon!
なんか、ノエルとフレアは...
Wait, what about Noel and Flare?
小悪魔じゃなくて？
Not a little devil?
なんかドタドタした悪魔...
Some kind of clumsy devil...
変な悪魔行かないで、変な悪魔！
Don't make us weird devils!
嫌なやつだもん。
That's mean!
天使と悪魔どっちが好き、君たち？
Which do you guys like better, angels or devils?
あ、確かに！
Oh, true!
じゃあペンライトで言ってもらえば？天使の白、悪魔の赤とか言って。
Then why don't we have them show us with penlights? Like white for angels, red for devils.
あ、ペンライトね！
Oh, penlights!
白と赤かな？
White and red?
色的に。
Color-wise.
白と赤、あ、うん。
White and red, ah, yeah.
じゃあ、悪魔派は赤！天使派は白！
Okay, so the devil faction is red! The angel faction is white!
変えてー！
Change them!
じゃあ皆さん、変えてください！
So everyone, please change your colors!
変えてください！
Please change them!
赤か白か！お、でも結構いい感じに割れてる！
Red or white! Oh, but they're pretty evenly split!
若干、赤が多い？
Maybe red is slightly more?
おー！
Oh!
あれ、悪魔のほうが人気？
Wait, are devils more popular?
いや、でも結構半分半分！半分半分くらい割れてるね！
No, but it's pretty much half and half! It's split about 50-50!
すげー！
Amazing!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
うれしい、ありがとう！
We're happy, thank you!
じゃあ、今日いいね、悪魔な感じも。
Well, the devil vibe is great today too.
うん、悪魔もいいね！
Yeah, devils are nice too!
ということで、Day 1に引き続き、バンドも生演奏となっております！
So, continuing from Day 1, the band is also performing live!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
かっこいいですね、これね！
It looks so cool, doesn't it?!
ありがとうございます！嬉しいです！
Thank you so much! We're so happy!
そしてね、配信のコメントももちろん見えてますよー！
And of course, we can see the streaming comments too!
見えてるよー！みんなー！
We can see you! Hey everyone!
もちろん、会場のみんなももちろん！
And of course, everyone in the venue as well!
見えてるよー！可愛いー！
We can see you! So cute!
みんな素敵な気合の入った推し活ファッションしてきてくれて…
Thank you all for dressing up in your wonderful...
…推し活ファッションしてきてくれてありがとー！
...passionate fan outfits! Thank you so much!
最高、最高ですよ！ / 最高ですね！
This is the best, simply the best! / It really is!
でも、ちょっぱなね、シャッフルメドレーでしたけど！
But right off the bat, we had the shuffle medley!
そうよー！ / 凄かったよね！ / 盛り上がったよね！
That's right! It was amazing, wasn't it?! / It was so hyped!
外でもですね、なんとですね…ここまでで、えっ？
But you know, surprisingly... up to this point, wait, what?
冒頭無料チラ見せが…
The free sneak peek at the beginning is...
嘘でしょ！？ / 嘘、嘘！？
No way?! / Are you lying?!
そんなの嘘ぺこ！ / …終了となります。
That's a lie, peko! / ...coming to an end.
嘘ってことで、ここからは… / 嘘ではないぺこですね。
Since it's a 'lie', from here on... / So it's not a lie, peko...
みんな観たいと思ってくれてると思うから…
I'm sure everyone wants to keep watching...
…概要欄に配信チケットのリンクがあるので！
...so there's a stream ticket link in the description!
今ポチポチっと買ってみてください！ / お願いします！
Please go click and buy them now! / Please!
後悔させない！今日はすごい！
We won't make you regret it! Today is going to be amazing!
今日は、Day 1よりもっと凄くなってますから！
Today is going to be even more incredible than Day 1!
もうぶち上げぶち上げで！
We're going to hype it up completely!
そう、Day 1とは違ったね、凄さ、盛り上がり。
Exactly. A totally different level of excitement from Day 1.
君たちも今日超ぶち上がりなんで…
Since you guys are also super hyped up today...
…頑張って最後まで息切れしないようにぶち上がってください！
...do your best to keep rising and don't run out of breath!
最後までしっかり声出してね！ / 出してねー！
Make sure to shout until the very end! / Raise your voices!
そしてね、配信で楽しんでる人は…
And for those enjoying the stream...
…ハッシュタグ『ぎゅーるるん大作戦Day2』でいっぱい呟いてください！
...please tweet a lot with the hashtag #Kyu-ru-runGreatOpsDay2!
はー…どきどきするね。
Wow, my heart is pounding.
そろそろいいですか？次の曲にいってもいいでしょうか？
Is it about time? Shall we move on to the next song?
いきましょう！ / はーい！
Let's go! / Yes!
なんと次の曲は、私からスタートさせていただきたいと…
Unbelievably, the next song will start with me...
…何が来るんでしょうか！ / 何だろう何だろう！ / いきましょう！
...What could it be?! / I wonder what it is! / Let's go!
フルメドレー！
Full medley!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!